Bhavesh Patel

A results-oriented Software Engineer with over **4 years of experience** in the IT SaaS Product Industry, with a focus on backend and distributed systems. Platform development, architecture, agile techniques, cloud services, and web-based applications are all areas where you need to be well-versed.

EXPERIENCE

Jio Haptik Technologies Ltd, Mumbai

April 2021 - Present : Software Developer III - Backend

For the Analytics tool, I designed and developed end-to-end software architectures and
product features. I'm responsible for datalake's data architecture and handling all aspects
of it. I'm presently mentoring a junior and working on the NiFi tool, which allows clients to
incorporate analytical data streams into their own ETL processes.

July 2019 - March 2021 : Software Developer II - Backend

- Using Django, collaborated with the platform team to build tools for Bot Building, Live Agent Tool, and Analytics Tool (Python). Improvements to current tools' search capabilities, as well as a feedback gathering path.
- Worked on numerous features with the Live Agent Chat Platform, including redesigning
 the whole performance dashboard and using Elasticsearch's performance for real-time
 measurements, as well as upgrading the module for creating analytics reports.
- Participated in all aspects of the SDLC, including systems planning, design, programming, testing, and documentation.

School of Accelerated Learning (soal.io), Mumbai

Jan 2019 - Present: Catalyst & Instructor

- Catalyst & Instructor for Product Engineering Course
- Mock Interviews

AthenasOwl - Quantiphi, Inc., Mumbai

July 2017 - July 2019 : Software Developer

- Using Django, I created microservices using reusable, testable, and efficient code.
- The task was to define the microservices-based application's component of the architecture/system design. Conducting code reviews and documentation that is effective.
- The microservices were set up and deployed using GCP/AWS. Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Functions, Google Pub Sub, and orchestration are all skills that you should have.
- In charge of a team of three Software Developers and assisting with technical issues.
- Managing and owning the client's end-to-end delivery. Contributing to the product plan and learning about different elements of the product life cycle.

CONTACT

+91 889 890 4660 bhaveshpatel640@gmail.com LinkedIn: bhaveshpatel640 GitHub: @bhaveshpatel640 https://bhaveshpatel.xyz

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Django, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Linux, GCP/AWS, ELK stack, JavaScript, Docker, Web Development (HTML/CSS), Bash Scripting, CI/CD, RabbitMQ / Celery, Git, NiFi

PERSONAL & MANAGEMENT SKILLS

- Willingness to learn and explore new technologies and implement them.
- As being part of a software delivery team, good at project management always kept track of scope, cost & delivered on or before deadlines.
- Good Analytical & Problem-solving skills.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Google's Associate Cloud Engineer
 Certification.
- Awarded with rising star 2018 at Quantiphi, Inc.

ACADEMICS PROJECTS

- TransFile: Android application that allows you to transfer files to PC wirelessly
- Newsplate: Google's Associate Cloud Engineer Certification.

EDUCATION

- Sardar Patel Institute of Technology, Mumbai
 B.E. (Computer Engineering, 2013 2017)
 8.36/10 CGPA
- Thakur College of Science & Commerce,
 HSC (Junior College, IT, 2011 2013)
 84.67%
- Samata Vidya Mandir, SSC (2000 2011)
 87.64%

Freelance Developer, Mumbai

Jan 2019 - Present: Software Engineer & Cloud Consultant

- Worked on bespoke automation scripts, web development, end-to-end inventory
 management with customised automation scripts, and developed custom dashboards
 utilising Google Spreadsheet, App Scripts, and Data Studio with 5+ clients on various
 projects.
- Several websites and layouts built with Bootstrap. Several clients were consulted, and a suitable solution was offered.

INTERNSHIPS / PROJECTS

Cirtru Classifieds Pvt Ltd., Mumbai (1.5 Month): Software Developer

 I began by studying the AngularJS framework. Created a more user-friendly website and interactive components, as well as fixing mobile/desktop views and several significant UI issues, as well as adding new widget functionality. Browserstack tools were used for cross-browser testing.